<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Manifestos on The Kade Collective</title>
    <link>http://madebykade.com/manifesto/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Manifestos on The Kade Collective</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2017 14:34:28 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://madebykade.com/manifesto/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Profit Sharing</title>
      <link>http://madebykade.com/manifesto/profit-sharing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2017 14:34:28 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebykade.com/manifesto/profit-sharing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Purpose of this page: this page describes how full time employees are compensated once they become part of the Kade Collective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transparency Policy</title>
      <link>http://madebykade.com/manifesto/transparency-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebykade.com/manifesto/transparency-policy/</guid>
      <description> Internal transparency Everyone who is part of the Kade Collective practices Radical Condor. This means that we are 100% transparent internally. Everything to do with strategy and personal performance is discussed openly.
Public facing transparency The following is public
 Salaries Profit Revenues Traffic General Practices  What are the exceptions?  Company valuations (this is because it may scare off investors. If their appetitie is public, then it could harm them when trying to close deals in the future) If a project does not directly belong to us, we will only expose information that already publicly available We will not expose any practices which give us a competitive advantage  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frat House</title>
      <link>http://madebykade.com/manifesto/frat-house/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2017 14:34:28 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebykade.com/manifesto/frat-house/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Purpose of this page: this page describes how the incubator works. TL;DR: Kade will incubate other companies in exchange for 10% equity. Kade will provide seed capital, expertise, and access to all collective assets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retirement Fund</title>
      <link>http://madebykade.com/manifesto/retirement-fund/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2017 14:34:28 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebykade.com/manifesto/retirement-fund/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Purpose of this page: this page describes profits are invested into a Retirement fund. Partners earn shares in this fund each month. 5% of monthly profit is automatically invested into Exchange Traded Funds. Partners vest shares in this fund every month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sport Star Policy</title>
      <link>http://madebykade.com/manifesto/the-sport-star-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebykade.com/manifesto/the-sport-star-policy/</guid>
      <description> Overview  Sport stars must be high performers Sport stars are team players Sport stars look after themselves.  They take time of when you need it  Sport stars love what they do  Get back to work as soon as they are ready   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collective Assets</title>
      <link>http://madebykade.com/manifesto/collective-assets/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2017 14:34:28 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebykade.com/manifesto/collective-assets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Purpose of this page: to outline the key assets that all members of the Kade Collective have at their disposal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reasonable Person Policy</title>
      <link>http://madebykade.com/manifesto/reasonable-person-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2017 14:34:28 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebykade.com/manifesto/reasonable-person-policy/</guid>
      <description> Nothing to see here &amp;hellip; yet
Only argue with people who seek the truth </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running Projects in Silos</title>
      <link>http://madebykade.com/manifesto/running-projects-in-silos/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2017 14:34:28 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebykade.com/manifesto/running-projects-in-silos/</guid>
      <description>Profits are paid monthly to Partners in the Kade Collective. This frequency gives the Collective a mindset to incrementally improve the parts of the business that makes it more successful. This policy creates a challenge in that we need track each project individually for continuous improvement.
All projects are tracked via Google Analytics and Compass. Each project is siloed to cover the key aspects of the project&amp;rsquo;s health:
 Revenue Expenses Traffic Customer Acquisition Cost (CAC) Lifetime Value (LTV)  Additional ways of separating  AWS tags: https://aws.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>30 minute rule</title>
      <link>http://madebykade.com/manifesto/30-minute-rule/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebykade.com/manifesto/30-minute-rule/</guid>
      <description>When you get stuck, you should spend 30 mins trying to solve it yourself
After you have spent 30 mins, you must reach out for help
when you reach out for help you should state the things that you have tried when you have a problem you should always present 3 possible solutions</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The &#34;Fristy&#34; Protocol</title>
      <link>http://madebykade.com/manifesto/the-fristy-protocol/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebykade.com/manifesto/the-fristy-protocol/</guid>
      <description>Nothing to see here &amp;hellip; yet</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Evaluation Framework</title>
      <link>http://madebykade.com/manifesto/the-evaluation-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebykade.com/manifesto/the-evaluation-framework/</guid>
      <description>Generally a set of &amp;ldquo;company values&amp;rdquo; are useless. The only value we hold at Kade is improvement. Outside of that, individuals are welcome to improve in whatever they believe in. Below is a broad range of attributes that an individual can focus on which we believe contributes the most to themselves and the team.
Each atrribute represents one of many day-to-day practices that a team member with have, and they are grouped into three broad &amp;ldquo;roles&amp;rdquo; - Business Owner, Team Leader, and High Performer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Routine</title>
      <link>http://madebykade.com/manifesto/weekly-routine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebykade.com/manifesto/weekly-routine/</guid>
      <description>Mandatory Daily: scrum Wednesday: workday
Optional Tuesday Planning day - what work to do tomorrow
Friday  Manifesto retrospective - make changes to the manifesto Swarming  Superstars (go up) vs rockstars (go out) - thought partners: how to manage Superstars</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://madebykade.com/manifesto/readme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebykade.com/manifesto/readme/</guid>
      <description>The Kade Collective manifesto See more at http://madebykade.com/manifesto
Our manifesto is an open declaration of how we intend to operate. It is as mutuable as any policy that is confronted with the real world.
The manifesto is not designed to be universally applicable. It is designed to see how a group of like minded people work together while learning a few things about organisational theory along the way. It is strongly shaped by our past experience and iteratively improved upon as we continue to work together.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>