<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Kade Collective</title>
    <link>http://madebykade.com/categories/manifesto-practices/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Kade Collective</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://madebykade.com/categories/manifesto-practices/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Running Projects in Silos</title>
      <link>http://madebykade.com/manifesto/running-projects-in-silos/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2017 14:34:28 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebykade.com/manifesto/running-projects-in-silos/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Profits are paid monthly to Partners in the Kade Collective. This frequency gives the Collective a mindset to incrementally improve the parts of the business that makes it more successful. This policy creates a challenge in that we need track each project individually for continuous improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All projects are tracked via Google Analytics and Compass. Each project is siloed to cover the key aspects of the project&amp;rsquo;s health:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Revenue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expenses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Traffic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Customer Acquisition Cost (CAC)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lifetime Value (LTV)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;additional-ways-of-separating&#34;&gt;Additional ways of separating&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AWS tags: &lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/aws-cost-allocation/&#34;&gt;https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/aws-cost-allocation/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Evaluation Framework</title>
      <link>http://madebykade.com/manifesto/the-evaluation-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebykade.com/manifesto/the-evaluation-framework/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Generally a set of &amp;ldquo;company values&amp;rdquo; are useless. The only value we hold at Kade is &lt;strong&gt;improvement&lt;/strong&gt;. Outside of that, individuals are welcome to improve in whatever they believe in. Below is a broad range of attributes that an individual can focus on which we believe contributes the most to themselves and the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each atrribute represents one of many day-to-day practices that a team member with have, and they are grouped into three broad &amp;ldquo;roles&amp;rdquo; - Business Owner, Team Leader, and High Performer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;business-owner&#34;&gt;Business Owner&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Diligent: Responsible, self motivating, and self disciplined&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Egoless: seeks what is best for Kade even when it doesn&amp;rsquo;t satisfy their own ego&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enjoyable: Contributes to culture&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Curious: Seeks to understand all parts of the business&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Humble: Cleans the dishes and picks up trash&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sensible: thinks sustainably; incrementally; long term; commercially&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inspiring: inspires others through work ethic and contribution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Honest: doesn&amp;rsquo;t talk about people behind their backs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Candid: gives critical feedback well&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Calm: if you always look busy it&amp;rsquo;s because you&amp;rsquo;re out of control. Don&amp;rsquo;t be busy, be focused&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;team-leader&#34;&gt;Team Leader&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adaptive: Owns and adapts processes to become more effective to increase output&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grows the team: Shares workload with team - sets context and offloads tasks when appropriate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shares the load: picks up work from others when workload is imbalanced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Patient: lets others complete tasks (even when they can do it themselves) so that the team improves as a whole&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Effective: pushes back on tasks that aren&amp;rsquo;t a priority or shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be done&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Efficient: courage to question processes and minimise complexity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Self-aware: Honest and quick to admit mistakes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Charitable: Makes time to help colleagues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maven: Shares information proactively&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stoic: Maintains calm when under stress&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Embraces diverse working styles. Realises that improvement and conformity are not always related&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Astute: makes the most of people&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;high-performer&#34;&gt;High Performer&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Huge output: accomplishes amazing amounts of important work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Studious: a great learner who is always improving&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Effective: Smartly prioritize your work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consistent: colleagues can rely on you&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gets shit done: Focuses on results rather than getting caught up in the process&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Holistic: Contributes outside your specialty&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Risk taker: Takes smart risks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Autonomous: Can operate in solo when required. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t require need to be told what to do or require constant input from other team members&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creative: Creates idea and strategies that will benefit the company&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;notable-exclusions&#34;&gt;Notable exclusions:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fun: Fun is a function of actions and not a personal trait. This is incorporated into&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kindness: TBD&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;benefits-of-evaluation&#34;&gt;Benefits of evaluation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each partner can get a objective view of the area they can improve&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Colleagues take time to notice the things that you do well&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;typical-archetypes&#34;&gt;Typical archetypes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Possible outcomes to watch out for. Usually noticing this in yourself is enough to correct any bad habits&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-consultant-strong-performer-weak-team-leader&#34;&gt;The Consultant - Strong Performer, Weak Team Leader&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This attitude is typically makes a person non-expendable due to their huge work output, but can be quite selfish in terms of their work.
They will rarely share their work with others in a effort to make themselves more valued/non-expendable
They usually fail to recognise that being the only one in the team that has their skills/knowledge is not a good thing
These people are can be Strong Business Owners too - usually very disciplined or work long hours&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Motivations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“I only want to share / say when I master this”

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coachable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“this is the only thing that kept me ahead in the team”

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;make the team “safe” and people feel secured and not comparing with each other but competing with world-class external benchamark&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-friend-strong-business-owner-weak-performer&#34;&gt;The Friend - Strong Business Owner, Weak Performer&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the hard working and affable colleague
They usually give a 110% to their work and are extremely likeable&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Motivations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;I know I can&amp;rsquo;t keep up with the team so I will work extra hard&amp;rdquo;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Determine whether they can upskill quickly or not&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Self awareness is low - believes they are performing well even though the are not

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Call out early - give them feedback&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-delegator-strong-team-leader-weak-performer&#34;&gt;The Delegator - Strong Team Leader, Weak Performer&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This person is great at telling you how much work they are doing
They usually offload their tasks to others, or worse they do the work and it is low quality and has to be redone later on by other team members&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Motivations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Self awareness is low - believes they are performing well even though the are not

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Call out early - give them feedback&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-idealist-strong-business-owner-weak-team-leader-and-weak-performer&#34;&gt;The Idealist - Strong Business Owner, Weak Team Leader and weak performer&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Needs improvement: there is nothing wrong with being an Idealist. You must be consistent and back up what you say though
This person is great at inspiring others
Overall this person lacks consistency
Great with large crowds and usually one on one - normally not great at managing or working in a team or interpersonal dynamics&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Routine</title>
      <link>http://madebykade.com/manifesto/weekly-routine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebykade.com/manifesto/weekly-routine/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;mandatory&#34;&gt;Mandatory&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daily: scrum
Wednesday: workday&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;optional&#34;&gt;Optional&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;tuesday&#34;&gt;Tuesday&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Planning day - what work to do tomorrow&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;friday&#34;&gt;Friday&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manifesto retrospective - make changes to the manifesto&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Swarming&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>