<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Manifesto Practices on The Kade Collective</title>
    <link>http://madebykade.com/categories/manifesto-practices/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Manifesto Practices on The Kade Collective</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2017 14:34:28 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://madebykade.com/categories/manifesto-practices/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Running Projects in Silos</title>
      <link>http://madebykade.com/manifesto/running-projects-in-silos/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2017 14:34:28 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebykade.com/manifesto/running-projects-in-silos/</guid>
      <description>Profits are paid monthly to Partners in the Kade Collective. This frequency gives the Collective a mindset to incrementally improve the parts of the business that makes it more successful. This policy creates a challenge in that we need track each project individually for continuous improvement.
All projects are tracked via Google Analytics and Compass. Each project is siloed to cover the key aspects of the project&amp;rsquo;s health:
 Revenue Expenses Traffic Customer Acquisition Cost (CAC) Lifetime Value (LTV)  Additional ways of separating  AWS tags: https://aws.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>30 minute rule</title>
      <link>http://madebykade.com/manifesto/30-minute-rule/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebykade.com/manifesto/30-minute-rule/</guid>
      <description>When you get stuck, you should spend 30 mins trying to solve it yourself
After you have spent 30 mins, you must reach out for help
when you reach out for help you should state the things that you have tried when you have a problem you should always present 3 possible solutions</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Evaluation Framework</title>
      <link>http://madebykade.com/manifesto/the-evaluation-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebykade.com/manifesto/the-evaluation-framework/</guid>
      <description>Generally a set of &amp;ldquo;company values&amp;rdquo; are useless. The only value we hold at Kade is improvement. Outside of that, individuals are welcome to improve in whatever they believe in. Below is a broad range of attributes that an individual can focus on which we believe contributes the most to themselves and the team.
Each atrribute represents one of many day-to-day practices that a team member with have, and they are grouped into three broad &amp;ldquo;roles&amp;rdquo; - Business Owner, Team Leader, and High Performer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Routine</title>
      <link>http://madebykade.com/manifesto/weekly-routine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebykade.com/manifesto/weekly-routine/</guid>
      <description>Mandatory Daily: scrum Wednesday: workday
Optional Tuesday Planning day - what work to do tomorrow
Friday  Manifesto retrospective - make changes to the manifesto Swarming  Superstars (go up) vs rockstars (go out) - thought partners: how to manage Superstars</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>